Inventory of the Yonah Alexander papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Potomac Institute materials, 1996-2013 (Boxes 25-48)
  - Potomac Institute publications, 2002-2013 (Boxes 25-46)
    - Turkey's Counterterrorism Strategies, 2009 (Box-folder 46: 9)
    - Turkish-U.S. Strategic Partnership, 2010 (Box-folder 46: 10)
    - Understanding the Unleashed Dragon (Box-folder 46: 11)
    - UN Palestinian Statehood draft, 2011 (Box-folder 46: 12)
    - Update Newsletter, 2001 (Box-folder 46: 13)
    - Usama bin Laden's al-Qaida: A Profile of a Terrorist Network, 2001 (Box-folder 46: 14)
    - Why the Maghreb Matters final report, 2009 (Box-folder 46: 15)
  - Potomac Institute Records, 1996-2006 (Boxes 46-47)
    Includes proposals, press releases, and other internal records from the International Center for Terrorism Studies at the Potomac Institute for Policy Studies.
    - 403(b) Plan Summary Plan Description, 2006 (Box-folder 46: 16)
    - Book series proposal for Oceana Book Series, 2000 (Box-folder 46: 17)
    - Countering Biological Terrorism proposal, 1996 (Box-folder 46: 18)
    - Electronic distribution project proposal, 2001 (Box-folder 46: 19)
    - Foreign affinity terrorism annual report, 2003 (Box-folder 46: 20)
    - "Information Mining and Management" proposal, 2001 (Box-folder 46: 21)
    - "Information Warfare" proposal, 2000 (Box-folder 47: 1)
    - International Center for Terrorism Studies background materials, 2001-2008 (Box-folder 47: 2)
    - Press releases, 2004 (Box-folder 47: 3)
    - Research project proposals, 2000 (Box-folder 47: 4)
    - "Weapons of Mass Destruction Detection" study, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 47: 5-6)
  - Potomac Institute Conference Materials, 1996-2012 (Boxes 47-48)
    Includes conference materials, including papers, summary documentation, reports, pamphlets, and handouts from various conferences sponsored by the Potomac Institute for Policy Studies, arranged alphabetically by conference title.
    - al-Qaida: Quo Vadis? Conference, 2012 (Box-folder 47: 7-8)
    - Ambassador's Forum luncheon transcript, 2010 (Box-folder 47: 9)
    - Various conference programs, 2007-2011 (Box-folder 47: 10)
    - "Countering Biological Terrorism" conference, 1997 (Box-folder 47: 11-12)
    - "Countering Transnational Threats" senior advisory panel, 1998 (Box-folder 47: 13-14, 48: 1)
    - "Foreign Affinity Terrorism" conference planning materials, 2003 (Box-folder 48: 2-3)
    - "Future Warfare 20XX" conference, 2000 (Box-folder 48: 4)
    - "Piracy and Maritime Terrorism" conference, 2009 (Box-folder 48: 5)
    - Planning documentation, 1996-2011 (Box-folder 48: 6)
    - "Role of Intelligence in War and Peace" conference, 2000 (Box-folder 48: 7)
- George Washington University materials, 1993-1998 (Boxes 48-49)
  Includes conference materials, pamphlets, reports, and background materials from the Terrorism Studies Program at George Washington University.
  - George Washington University conference materials, 1993-1998 (Boxes 48-49)
    - "Aviation Security" conference materials, 1997 (Box-folder 48: 8-11)
    - "Current Issues on International Trade", 1996-1998 (Box-folder 49: 1-5)
    - Program draft, 1997 (Box-folder 49: 6)
    - Conference materials, 1993-1996 (Box-folder 49: 7)
  - "Preventing Super Terrorism" report, 1995 (Box-folder 49: 8)
  - "Worker's Party of Kurdistan" report, 1996 (Box-folder 49: 9)
  - Terrorism Studies Program materials, 1997 (Box-folder 49: 10)
- Inter-University Center for Terrorism Studies Materials, 1997-2012 (Boxes 49-50)
  Includes conference materials, publications, drafts of publications, and internal documents from the Inter-University Center for Terrorism Studies at the Potomac Institute for Policy Studies.
  - Case study on the Sahrawi refugees, 2009 (Box-folder 49: 11)
  - Program, 2012 (Box-folder 49: 12)
  - Proposal for founding, 2011 (Box-folder 49: 13)
  - Background materials, 1997-2008 (Box-folder 49: 14)
  - Background materials, 2002-2010 (Box-folder 49: 15)
  - Conference materials, 2007-2010 (Box-folder 49: 16)
  - Challenges for Western Security, 1999 (Box-folder 49: 17)
  - CounterTerrorism Strategies for the 21st Century, 1999 (Box-folder 49: 18)
  - Intern history, 2006-2008 (Box-folder 50: 1)
  - Latin America's Security, 2009 (Box-folder 50: 2)
  - Partnership for Peace Review manuscript, 2011 (Box-folder 50: 3)
  - Partnership for Peace Review Volume 1 Number 1, 2010 (Box-folder 50: 4)
  - Preventing Super Terrorism, 1997 (Box-folder 50: 5)
  - Program, 2012 (Box-folder 50: 6)
  - Terrorism: an Electronic Journal and Knowledge Base draft, 2012 (Box-folder 50: 7)
  - "Threats of a Technological Age: Cyber Terrorism and Super Terrorism" conference materials, 1998 (Box-folder 50: 8)
  - "Venezuelistan: Iran's Latin American Ambitions" conference materials, 2010 (Box-folder 50: 9)
- Subject File, 1969-2008 (Boxes 50-52)
  Includes rare printed matter and publications arranged alphabetically regarding terrorism in specific geographical locations or regarding specific organizations.
  - Afghanistan and Terrorism, 1990 (Box-folder 50: 10)
  - African Terrorism Data, 2007 (Box-folder 50: 11)
  - Armenian Terrorism (Box-folder 50: 12)
  - Domestic Terrorism, 1999 (Box-folder 50: 13)
  - Euskadi Ta Askatasuna (ETA), 2008 (Box-folder 50: 14)
  - Hamas, 1993-2001 (Box-folder 51: 1)
  - Hizbollah, 1986 (Box-folder 51: 2)
  - India, 1988 (Box-folder 51: 3)
  - Iraq, 2004 (Box-folder 51: 4)
  - Israel, 1986-1992 (Box-folder 51: 5)
  - Japanese Red Army, 1997 (Box-folder 51: 6-7)
  - Kurdistan Worker's Party, 1992-1999 (Box-folder 51: 8-9)
  - Lebanon, 1969-1982 (Box-folder 51: 10)
  - Minority Rights Group materials, 1994 (Box-folder 51: 11)
  - Palestinian Liberation Organization, 1974-1990 (Box-folder 52: 1-2)
  - Politics of Death Study, 1990 (Box-folder 52: 3)
  - Revolutionary People's Liberation Party-Front Magazine, 1994 (Box-folder 52: 4)
  - Sri Lankan Terrorism, 1998-2001 (Box-folder 52: 5)
  - Witness for Peace Report, 1990 (Box-folder 52: 6)
- Printed Materials, 1966-2009 (Boxes 52-56)
  Contains printed matter, including rare publications, newsletters, books, and pamphlets arranged alphabetically by title.
  - Al Awdah English Weekly, 1987 (Box-folder 52: 7)
  - American Spectator, 1980 (Box-folder 52: 8)
  - Arab News and Views, 1969 (Box-folder 52: 9)
  - Arab Press Bulletin, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 52: 10)
  - Assassinations Commissioned by Belgrade, 1981 (Box-folder 52: 11)
  - Avrasya Dosyasi, 2000 (Box-folder 52: 12)
  - Burma Alert, 1994 (Box-folder 52: 13)
  - Canadian Middle East Digest, 1986 (Box-folder 52: 14)
  - Clandestine Tactics and Technology, 1976-1982 (Box-folder 52: 15)
  - Colombia Besieged, 1989 (Box-folder 52: 16)
  - The Communist Insurgency in the Philippines, 1985 (Box-folder 53: 1)
  - Conflict Studies, 1980 - 1988 (Box-folder 53: 2)
  - Counterterrorism Intelligence Report, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 53: 3)
  - Crossroads, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 53: 4)
  - Defense Against Terrorism Review, 2009 (Box-folder 53: 5)
  - E/SA Engage Social Action, 1986 (Box-folder 53: 6)
  - Executive Risk Assessment Volume 2-3, 5, 1980-1983 (Box-folder 53: 7-9)
  - The Fight, 1994 (Box-folder 53: 10)
  - Global Terrorism and International Cooperation Symposium, 2008 (Box-folder 53: 11)
  - Greece and PKK Terrorism, 1999 (Box-folder 53: 12)
  - Guatemala Case Reports 1980-1985, 1986 (Box-folder 53: 13)
  - Human Rights and Freedoms in Ukraine, 1999 (Box-folder 53: 14)
  - Human Rights Bulletin, 1999 (Box-folder 53: 15)
  - Interdisciplinary Center Papers on Terrorism, 2002 (Box-folder 53: 16)
  - International Committee of the Red Cross As Guardian, 1998 (Box-folder 54: 1)
  - In the Grip of the Sandinistas, 1989 (Box-folder 54: 2)
  - Jaffee Center Materials, 1984-2000 (Box-folder 54: 3)
  - Jezreel's Call, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 54: 4)
  - Joint Publications Research Service (JPRS) Report on Terrorism, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 54: 5-7)
  - Liberation Arafat Style, 1977 (Box-folder 54: 8)
  - LTTE In the Eyes of the World, 1997 (Box-folder 54: 9)
  - Makka Calling, 1985 (Box-folder 54: 10)
  - MedNews, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 54: 11)
  - Middle East Focus, 1980 (Box-folder 54: 12)
  - Middle East International, 1991 (Box-folder 54: 13)
  - MidEast Information Resource, 1983 (Box-folder 54: 14)
  - Namah, 1993 (Box-folder 54: 15)
  - Near East Report, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 54: 16)
  - The Nicaraguan Report, 1989 (Box-folder 54: 17)
  - Northern Ireland: A War to be Won, 1984 (Box-folder 54: 18)
  - Outpost, 1996 (Box-folder 54: 19)
  - Palestine!, 1978 (Box-folder 54: 20)
  - Palestine Issue, 1966 (Box-folder 54: 21)
  - Palestine Newsletter Copies, 1986 (Box-folder 54: 22)
  - Palestine Resistance Bulletin, 1970 (Box-folder 54: 23)
  - Pinkerton Annual Risk Assessment, 1995 (Box-folder 55: 1)
  - P.L.O. Information Bulletin, 1987 (Box-folder 55: 2)
  - Professionalization of Peacekeeping, 1994 (Box-folder 55: 3)
  - Profile of Terrorist Violence in Jannu and Kashmir, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 55: 4-5)
  - Quarterly Risk Assessment, 1980-1984 (Box-folder 55: 6-7)
  - Revista Occidental, Year 10, Number 1, 1993 (Box-folder 55: 8)
  - Risk Assessment Monthly, 1988 (Box-folder 55: 9)
  - Risk Assessment Quarterly, 1988-1991 (Box-folder 55: 10)
  - Risk Assessment Weekly, 1988 (Box-folder 55: 11)
  - SIPRI (Stockholm International Peace Research Institute ) Continuity and Change book, 1996 (Box-folder 55: 12)
  - SIPRI (Stockholm International Peace Research Institute ), 1995 (Box-folder 56: 1)
  - Strategic Bulletin Quarterly, 1998 (Box-folder 56: 2)
  - State-Sponsored Terrorism: Threat and Possible Countermeasure, 1985 (Box-folder 56: 3)
  - Terror Update, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 56: 4)
  - Terrorism Violence Insurgency journal Volumes 1-4, 6-8, 1979 (Box-folder 56: 5-11)
  - Third World Forum, 1989 (Box-folder 56: 12)
  - Ukraine After the Orange Revolution book, 2005 (Box-folder 56: 13)
  - West Watch, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 56: 14)
  - Yaderny Kontrol (Nuclear Control) journal Volume 5 Number 1, 2000 (Box-folder 56: 15)
  - The Yesha Report, 1994 (Box-folder 56: 16)
- Oversize Material, 2005 (Oversize-box 57)
  Includes various undated posters advertising courses and conferences taught and chaired by Yonah Alexander, various posters in English and Arabic, various maps of Israel, and one copy of the Speakers' Demonstration Kit Israel and the Arab States.